<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Stefan Kendall</title>
    <link>http://stefankendall.com/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Stefan Kendall</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 16 Oct 2016 08:27:40 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://stefankendall.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>About Me</title>
      <link>http://stefankendall.com/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Oct 2016 08:27:40 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://stefankendall.com/about/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;brief&#34;&gt;Brief&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://stefankendall.com/files/profile.png&#34; width=&#34;100px&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been a software developer for about a decade and I live in Raleigh, NC.
I prefer iOS and web app development.
If you need a resume, go &lt;a href=&#34;http://stefankendall.com/files/resume.pdf&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;technology&#34;&gt;Technology&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I do not believe that a dumpster list of used, read-about, or heard-it-mentioned-once technologies
is any meaningful measure of a developer and actively hides more useful skills like project management,
picking the best tool for the job over what you know, and engineering principles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I like &lt;strong&gt;iOS&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;web app development&lt;/strong&gt;, but I&amp;rsquo;ve done full-stack at day jobs.
  I prefer to make things that &lt;strong&gt;impact users&lt;/strong&gt; directly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;unsorted-list-of-buzzwords-i-ve-used-recently&#34;&gt;unsorted list of buzzwords I&amp;rsquo;ve used recently&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;angular, javascript, iOS/most *Kit frameworks, swift, node, sails, mocha, jasmine, ruby, capybara, cucumber,
protractor, html, css, bootstrap, foundation, git, jenkins, teamcity, es6, bower, npm, yarn, hugo, grunt, gulp,
 markdown, react, java, gradle, tdd, agile, kanban, and the catcher in the rye.&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The future of the web is web components, and the future of software is leaning on platforms
 to build value. I&amp;rsquo;ll use the best tools for the job as they rapidly and repeatedly cycle in and out of use.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;stuff-i-don-t-use&#34;&gt;stuff I don&amp;rsquo;t use&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re looking for this experience or tech stack specifically, I&amp;rsquo;m &lt;em&gt;probably&lt;/em&gt; not interested.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;tech&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;why&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;

&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;.NET&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;This never seems the best option for the job given open-source alternatives&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;PHP&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s 2016 and I don&amp;rsquo;t work at facebook where I&amp;rsquo;d be using Hack anyway&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Android&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;The SDK/toolchain/simulators are awful&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; If the toolchain/sdks ever improve, I&amp;rsquo;ll reconsider my position.
In the meantime I would stick to &lt;a href=&#34;https://facebook.github.io/react-native/&#34;&gt;react native&lt;/a&gt; even though I normally caution against middleware.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;contact&#34;&gt;Contact&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Want to discuss an interesting project? Think I might be interested? E-mail me and let&amp;rsquo;s talk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;mailto: stefankendall@gmail.com&#34;&gt;stefankendall@gmail.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Steak Games</title>
      <link>http://stefankendall.com/project/steak-games/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Oct 2016 21:16:31 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://stefankendall.com/project/steak-games/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Understanding HTTP</title>
      <link>http://stefankendall.com/blog/understanding-http/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://stefankendall.com/blog/understanding-http/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;/car.cfc?id=1234&amp;amp;method=get&amp;amp;ReturnFormat=json&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;http&#34;&gt;HTTP&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It feels like I&amp;rsquo;ve been in a thousand discussions about web APIs, and I&amp;rsquo;ve explained the same few things over and over in each of those discussions. It&amp;rsquo;s 2016, and at this point I expect developers to have a loose grasp on how the internet works.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But whenever I&amp;rsquo;m talking to someone I haven&amp;rsquo;t worked with before, experience tells me that I should apply the following filter:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;We have a rest api&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo; &lt;strong&gt;[I doubt it]&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;ldquo;&amp;hellip;that returns json&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo;
&lt;strong&gt;[&lt;a href=&#34;http://json.org&#34;&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll be the judge of that&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;sup&gt;50&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;50&lt;/sub&gt; it&amp;rsquo;s actually JSONP or something else]&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;ldquo;&amp;hellip;that&amp;rsquo;s horizontally scalable&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo; &lt;strong&gt;[definitely isn&amp;rsquo;t]&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;ldquo;&amp;hellip;and follows current web standards.&amp;rdquo; &lt;strong&gt;[lol okay]&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m not going to go answer this here, but I may make this an interview question going forward. It doesn&amp;rsquo;t require any development to answer, and anyone with a reasonable grasp of how HTTP works will find at least 3 issues without breaking a sweat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Elite developer zen master ninja rockstars&amp;rdquo; will find more than 3 problems. Can you?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tabletop Simulator Backup</title>
      <link>http://stefankendall.com/project/tabletop-simulator-backup/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Aug 2016 21:19:20 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://stefankendall.com/project/tabletop-simulator-backup/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>npm install -g ttsbackup</title>
      <link>http://stefankendall.com/blog/ttsbackup/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://stefankendall.com/blog/ttsbackup/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So I published a tool on npm. If you play &lt;a href=&#34;http://store.steampowered.com/app/286160/&#34;&gt;Tabletop Simulator&lt;/a&gt; (and you probably should),
then you&amp;rsquo;ve probably downloaded a few &lt;a href=&#34;https://steamcommunity.com/workshop/browse/?appid=286160&#34;&gt;mods&lt;/a&gt; by now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are hundreds of great mods, but unfortunately the half life on any given mod is terrible. Mods disappear constantly, and that means you can&amp;rsquo;t play them any more, even if you installed them locally!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A mod breaks when:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;hellip;it gets popular and the creator hosted files on dropbox, and dropbox has transfer quotas.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;hellip;the author pulls the mod off of the workshop for any reason. Sorry!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;hellip;any of the places the author put files goes down. Like imgur. Or pastebin (lol). Or some random german website (this really happens). Or dropbox or google drive.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The point is that there are way too many points of failure, and there&amp;rsquo;s no reason for it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wouldn&amp;rsquo;t it be great if you could fully copy a mod locally, and host it on something like your personal dropbox? Even if you play with your friends &lt;strong&gt;all the time&lt;/strong&gt;, it&amp;rsquo;s incredibly unlikely you would ever hit your bandwidth limit. And if you do, I&amp;rsquo;m sure one of your friends has dropbox, too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is why &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.npmjs.com/package/ttsbackup&#34;&gt;ttsbackup&lt;/a&gt; exists.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead of losing mods you&amp;rsquo;ve played forever, you can download all their images and models, and then create a new mod file that points to your copies of the files. So the flow goes something like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;run ttsbackup&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;pick a mod&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;pick a download location&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;give a base url for the new mod (like &lt;code&gt;https://dl.dropboxusercontent.com/u/&amp;lt;youruserid/&lt;/code&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;pick a name for the mod backup&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And that&amp;rsquo;s it! You&amp;rsquo;ve saved a mod forever. No one can take it from you, and no shitty web host can go down to ruin game night.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If a mod has already become broken, there&amp;rsquo;s also a &amp;ldquo;ttsbackup recover&amp;rdquo; command, but it probably won&amp;rsquo;t work. Tabletop Simulator loads files a little weird; images in decks and bags don&amp;rsquo;t actually load until you pull them out of the deck or bag. So if you haven&amp;rsquo;t seen literally every card and model in a game, you don&amp;rsquo;t have the full game.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Backup your mods early and often, and you won&amp;rsquo;t lose them. Happy gaming!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;p.s: I&amp;rsquo;m considering making this a native mac app. I&amp;rsquo;d support windows, too, if not for every cross-platform UI framework being godawful in this nascent age of technology. Ah well.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Just Tabata</title>
      <link>http://stefankendall.com/project/just-tabata/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Mar 2016 08:22:25 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://stefankendall.com/project/just-tabata/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Just Tabata</title>
      <link>http://stefankendall.com/blog/just-tabata/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Mar 2016 22:34:43 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://stefankendall.com/blog/just-tabata/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Apps works best when they laser-focus on their core competency and cut the fluff. This sounds like a pointless truism, but most apps ignore this wisdom and build page after page of sliders and toggles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve even done this myself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recently I&amp;rsquo;ve started doing tabata-exercise bike intervals, and I combed the app store for something simple that did exactly one thing: keep track of tabata intervals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A tabata interval is this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For 20 seconds, work all out, then rest for 10 seconds.
Repeat this for 8 intervals, or 4 minutes of total work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So here&amp;rsquo;s the whole app:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img style=&#34;display:inline-block; width: 24%&#34; src=&#34;http://stefankendall.com/files/tabata1.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/img&gt;
&lt;img style=&#34;display:inline-block; width: 24%&#34; src=&#34;http://stefankendall.com/files/tabata2.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/img&gt;
&lt;img style=&#34;display:inline-block; width: 24%&#34; src=&#34;http://stefankendall.com/files/tabata3.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/img&gt;
&lt;img style=&#34;display:inline-block; width: 24%&#34; src=&#34;http://stefankendall.com/files/tabata4.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You don&amp;rsquo;t need anything more to do a tabata interval, so it doesn&amp;rsquo;t do anything more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Text is large and colors are bright so you can toss your phone on the ground and use the app without holding it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The time count is intentionally small so you focus on working and don&amp;rsquo;t &amp;ldquo;game&amp;rdquo; 20 second intervals. It&amp;rsquo;s &lt;strong&gt;20 seconds&lt;/strong&gt;. Keep working.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Interval changes have loud, obvious tones to indicate work and rest. The app respects your phone&amp;rsquo;s mute toggle if you don&amp;rsquo;t want to be the asshole at the gym.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tap targets are huge, way larger than the visible buttons, so you can quit or pause when your vision is fading from a max effort interval.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;All screens of the app work in portrait, landscape, and even docked on an iPad. The screen adjusts and eliminates elements to keep the interface clean.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are a million tabata apps, and everything I found was terrible. The app is free on the app store, so go &lt;a href=&#34;itms://itunes.apple.com/us/app/apple-store/id1095176883?mt=8&#34;&gt;download it now&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;P.S:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;size-classes&#34;&gt;Size Classes&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was the first time I&amp;rsquo;ve properly built views using size classes on iOS. It was clunky, a little buggy, and multiplied the cost of development considerably. In the end, though, I think it&amp;rsquo;s worth it. The days of portrait, landscape, and phone-only apps are over.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Building for &amp;ldquo;just portrait&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;just landscape&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;just iPhone&amp;rdquo; likely means your design isn&amp;rsquo;t very good and is doing too much. When apps have focus, and don&amp;rsquo;t resemble the canonically bad yahoo.com, you don&amp;rsquo;t need every single pixel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This means every screen is more expensive to design and build, and that&amp;rsquo;s probably a good thing. Apps that resemble junk drawers will explode in cost and become infeasible for most developers. I feel this will likely be an adjustment period for clients and managers used to faster turnaround for shitty web pages and shitty apps, but the days of publishing garbage are done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are enough dull tools in the world, and it&amp;rsquo;s time to start building some sharp ones.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>July - Agar.io</title>
      <link>http://stefankendall.com/blog/agario/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Aug 2015 23:33:20 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://stefankendall.com/blog/agario/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;If you haven&amp;rsquo;t played &lt;a href=&#34;http://agar.io&#34;&gt;agar.io&lt;/a&gt;, go do that now. Two months ago I played this game and thought it might work great on iOS. I checked the app store, and there were three clones, and none had multiplayer, the defining feature of the game.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I set out to build it myself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;video style=&#34;width:50%&#34; controls autoplay loop&gt;
  &lt;source src=&#34;http://stefankendall.com/files/agarish.mp4&#34; type=&#34;video/mp4&#34;&gt;
&lt;/video&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip;but halfway through the month, agar.io released their own app. It&amp;rsquo;s not that good, but it is popular. Both the iPhone and the iPad present a distinct challenge in translating the experience that works well when you can see a good portion of a large battlefield. When you shrink the view, it feels like you get eaten without any warning, and it&amp;rsquo;s just not very rewarding.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;business-model&#34;&gt;Business Model&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Agar runs on ads, which makes the experience less good than it could be. My plan was to allow for user-created images and charge for skin contact packs. Animal Crossing&amp;rsquo;s t-shirt design was the model I was looking to copy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because of the necessary server cost, there needed to be some way to keep revenue flowing to support the user base. Ads are one way to achieve this, but it doesn&amp;rsquo;t feel good.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;defeat&#34;&gt;Defeat&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are times when you should double down on investment, and times when you need to quit. Games are fun, but so few become widely profitable that it seems like a worse lottery ticket than even employee equity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;so-what-s-next&#34;&gt;So what&amp;rsquo;s next?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Good things. I won&amp;rsquo;t work on any projects I don&amp;rsquo;t believe in, since time is scarce and I don&amp;rsquo;t quite like putting hundreds of hours into building metaphorical sand castles. Only the builder cares about them, they&amp;rsquo;re extremely temporary, and if you leave the sand castle for even a little while, the tide washes it away.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Without a crystal clear vision of what to build next, I think I&amp;rsquo;ll take some time and see if I can help others make their visions into reality. I&amp;rsquo;m not giving up on games, but I need to be realistic on what I can do on my own. As an individual, there&amp;rsquo;s just too much to do. There is value in teams, and I may build one.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mini Golf</title>
      <link>http://stefankendall.com/blog/mini-golf/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jul 2015 23:40:27 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://stefankendall.com/blog/mini-golf/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;This was a busy month between work and my personal life, and halfway through the month I lost the drive to release a finished product. Nonetheless, I learned a lot and resolved to a commitment for what I&amp;rsquo;m building next.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But first the game.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;video style=&#34;width:50%&#34; controls autoplay loop&gt;
  &lt;source src=&#34;http://stefankendall.com/files/mini-golf.mp4&#34; type=&#34;video/mp4&#34;&gt;
&lt;/video&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;constraints&#34;&gt;Constraints&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Black &amp;amp; White&lt;/strong&gt;. The entire game is greyscale. I wanted to try and make something with minimal color that was also a game, but transparency made certain things a whole lot simpler. With only white and black, differentiating a ball from a hole is pretty tough.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Minimal interaction&lt;/strong&gt;. The entire game is drag and release; that&amp;rsquo;s it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;fun&#34;&gt;Fun&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I thought it would be interesting to focus on time in a mini-golf game rather than strokes, but in the end I realized how large and complex most mini-golf games actually are. I drew up three concept levels, but in the end I knew it just wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be that fun without either complex levels or changing level interactions that other mini-golf games all have.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It takes significant work to make mini-golf engaging; that was just out of scope.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;so-this-was-a-failure&#34;&gt;So this was a failure?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kind of. While I failed to publish anything this month, I also discovered an incredible opportunity and a project I think would be a truly fun, popular game on iOS were it to exist.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s hard to run full-speed toward an endpoint you don&amp;rsquo;t truly believe in, but there&amp;rsquo;s something that should exist in the world that doesn&amp;rsquo;t.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;so-what-s-next&#34;&gt;So what&amp;rsquo;s next?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A game. But it&amp;rsquo;s a quite a bit bigger than anything I&amp;rsquo;ve done. Why&amp;rsquo;s that? It needs&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Real-time multiplayer&lt;/strong&gt;. Latency is paramount, and updates need to be robust and at least seem fair if the player is on a weak connection.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Player customization of characters&lt;/strong&gt;. This is half the fun. This also means I need a way to store and update user data.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;but-how-can-you-make-this-in-a-month&#34;&gt;But how can you make this in a month?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I probably can&amp;rsquo;t. But I&amp;rsquo;ll learn a lot taking on this larger project, and I may even make something others enjoy playing at the end. But it&amp;rsquo;s going to take time. This is the perfect opportunity for me to go Swift-only and just bite that bullet while it&amp;rsquo;s still optional.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And while I tend to loathe node when it&amp;rsquo;s shoehorned into serving the function of Rails, poorly, it actually seems like a solid candidate for a back-end here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Servers and real-time and multiplayer, oh my! Many years ago I broke ground on an app that would span years and actually help people. I want to build something significant again. Maybe this is that, or maybe it isn&amp;rsquo;t, but I&amp;rsquo;ll know more in a month.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>April&#39;s game, Stock Story</title>
      <link>http://stefankendall.com/blog/stock-story/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 May 2015 22:52:24 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://stefankendall.com/blog/stock-story/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve always liked gamebooks and choose your own adventures.
&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Give_Yourself_Goosebumps&#34;&gt;Give Yourself Goosebumps&lt;/a&gt;
defined my childhood, and I can remember many of the stories and mechanics from the books.
Most recently I&amp;rsquo;ve loved the work of Inkle Studios on &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.inklestudios.com/80days/&#34;&gt;80 days&lt;/a&gt; and the
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.inklestudios.com/sorcery/&#34;&gt;Sorcery!&lt;/a&gt; series. These games are top in class in games currently made for the iPad. They hire real, actual writers for their games, and it shows. There are few &amp;ldquo;bad guys and egg heads&amp;rdquo; and deep stories in a branching, complex world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I thought it would be fun to play with some of the mechanics needed for a
choose your own adventure, so I built &lt;a href=&#34;https://itunes.apple.com/app/id988245189&#34;&gt;Stock Story&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://stefankendall.com/files/stockstory1.png&#34; style=&#34;display:inline-block;width:49%&#34;&gt;&lt;/img&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;http://stefankendall.com/files/stockstory2.png&#34; style=&#34;display:inline-block;width:49%&#34;&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;stock-content&#34;&gt;Stock Content&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the constraints I put on the project was using nothing but stock material, aside from the story. All audio, images, and even the app icon are built using content from&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://shutterstock.com&#34;&gt;shutterstock&lt;/a&gt; ($143/month) and &lt;a href=&#34;http://audioblocks.com&#34;&gt;audioblocks&lt;/a&gt; ($99/year).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The audio for the project was a much better deal than the images, although you might recognize a few on other parts of the site. As it turns out, inkle studios offers a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.inklestudios.com/inklewriter/&#34;&gt;choose your own adventure book creator for free&lt;/a&gt;. Build your story, then publish to kindle for some small fee or output a json file that you can use however you want. Markers, conditionals, paragraph joining - it has it all. This saved a significant part of the challenge of the project, since all I had to do was write a json file handler instead of build a story format myself. The json schema seemed odd at first until I realized how incredibly robust it is for crafting any kind of story.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;writing-is-hard&#34;&gt;Writing is hard&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And it takes a long time. All told, I wrote 4,129 words for the story with 17 unique endings. This didn&amp;rsquo;t leave much time for editing, and a huge portion of the game I thought I could build I had to cut.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;and-so-is-flowing-text&#34;&gt;&amp;hellip;and so is flowing text&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SpriteKit has no UILabel, no fancy-schmance auto-flowing auto-sizing line-wrapping class to display text. In SpriteKit, you get one line of text and you can set the font. Justification? Word wrap? What&amp;rsquo;s that? In the end I wound up computing string sizes and manually flowing text, which wasn&amp;rsquo;t the best and really made me appreciate the tools we have that make these sorts of problems trivial in normal applications&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I tip my hat to you, whichever team built UILabel. You the real MVP.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;and-so-is-scrolling&#34;&gt;&amp;hellip;and so is scrolling&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You open Facebook.app/Twitter.app and scroll up and down willy-nilly. Items pop into view and everything is smooth and wonderful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SpriteKit has no UIScrollView. I didn&amp;rsquo;t have the time to build a solution myself, so each adventure is a one-way trip.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;retrospective&#34;&gt;Retrospective&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-good&#34;&gt;The Good&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stock images are better than you think, and they have more uses than late night commercial filler. I see stock images EVERYWHERE now, and I&amp;rsquo;m amazed how much I missed this before.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Audioblocks is super cool and very inexpensive. I now have a go-to for both games and apps/demos/software.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I&lt;/strong&gt; wrote a (short) story! Good or bad, &lt;strong&gt;I&lt;/strong&gt; hit the release button. &lt;strong&gt;I&lt;/strong&gt; am now hyper-aware of sentences &lt;strong&gt;I&lt;/strong&gt; write that begin with &lt;strong&gt;I&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-bad&#34;&gt;The Bad&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I am not a good writer&lt;/strong&gt;. I do believe it&amp;rsquo;s a skill that can be improved, so I hope to do that. I&amp;rsquo;ve downloaded &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.audible.com/pd/Self-Development/Writing-Great-Fiction-Storytelling-Tips-and-Techniques-Audiobook/B00P026PZC&#34;&gt;Writing Great Fiction: Storytelling Tips and Techniques&lt;/a&gt; as a first step toward learning to tell better stories. Stories permeate everything: video, documentation, debate, discussion, and even sales. People love stories, so it&amp;rsquo;s important to learn how to tell them.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;More a tech demo, less a game. &lt;em&gt;Sorcery!&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;80 days&lt;/em&gt; both have mechanics that make them more than just choose your own adventures, but while I tried to add a little extra by adding mini-games, I only had time to build one, so that fell flat.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-next-game&#34;&gt;The Next Game&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The start of each month will serve as a time to look back on the last game and plan the next. This leaves about two weeks for development and a week for release: screenshots, app icons, and the other hoops required to publish an app. So what&amp;rsquo;s the next game? I&amp;rsquo;d like to build a proper side scroller, and maybe look into game center if I have the time.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>